If we look at the string representation of some of these
built-in types that we've been working with, let's say I have a list here.
If I pass this into string, I get kind of nice human readable string representation.
Something we haven't talked about is repper.
If I pass the list into repper, this was string that looks a little bit different,
but let's try this.
So, as we build up our objects, these simple ones kind of have the same stir and repper.
But more advanced objects, you can think of the string value as the human readable string value.
Like, what would I put in here that would help other developers?
For repper, it's how would I tell Python to create a new instance of this class?
So, it's more kind of programmatic for the system, not necessarily for people to read.
And we'll see this as we work with more advanced objects, not really going to talk about dates today,
but this is part of the standard library.
So, the date time module.
And something you might see is, we want to get the current time right now.
So, this is the name of the module.
I'll need to import date time again, just like I did, you know, from cars import car.
This is like from date time import date time.
And I will call the now method on it.
If I look at the string of now, it will kind of give me this human readable date.
If I look at the repper, it's just going to give me what arguments I would need to pass in to make a new instance of it.
So, let's make a few, let's make a stir and a repper for our class.
We know that this dunder in it, I'm going to put them up here.
We know that this dunder in it method gets called under the hood when we create a new instance of our class.
If we're using this built in repper method on our class, how might we represent that in our class?
Also, with more dunders, more double X underscores.
So, if I have my Subaru now, before I put in either of these methods, it's going to print out this junk.
Totally unuseful.
It doesn't tell me anything about what's in the instance.
It just says, well, it's an object of a car, and it lives at this memory address.
We want to be friendly to other developers, we want to be friendly to ourselves.
So, let's make a string method first, and to do that, that's right, the double underscores.
Now, to represent the string representation of my instance, what am I going to need passed into this method?
Self.
That's right.
And then, I can don't want to use a print here, we want to return a string.
The print function does a call to display a value, but the print function itself actually doesn't return a value.
So, a little bit of an important distinction here.
If I assigned a value to print the print statement, it would do the print out, but if I checked the type of X, it's none.
Does that make sense as to why?
Yeah.
So, in the string method, we want to actually return a string.
And we're going to, we're going to, just put some stuff about our car in here, right?
Human readable doesn't really matter what, so I can say, you know, my car, the self.name.
Currently, self.
Self.
Runs.
Okay.
Now, scrolling to the top, I'm going to reload that.
Now, if I make a new car.
I can now call.
Stir on it.
And it prints something out.
And if I make a new Subaru.
It prints out that my car, the Subaru, right?
So, each instance prints out the values for each instance.
For wrapper.
We want to do things a little bit differently.
So, if I look at the date time.
The wrapper for the date time.
You can see that it's the class parentheses and all of the arguments that we need to instantiate it.
So, we would tend to do the same thing here.
And we would put, there's some kind of tricky Python ways to get the current class, but we're not going to use them right now.
We're just going to say, car.
We're going to put the parentheses here.
And in here, we're going to put self.
Need reload that.
So, now, if I make a new car.
Now, I can now call, stir on it.
How am I new Subaru?
I could call, repper on it as well.
And these underscore special underscore methods are tied into these built in methods in Python.
And as we saw earlier, we can make new instances as part of a list comprehension.
So, if I had a list of strings of numbers in here.
Oops.
A list of numbers.
I can say, I want to assign this to the variable.
I can do a list comprehension and say, for nom and nums.
Call int on each of those numbers.
Oops, I'm sorry.
So, I made a mistake here.
I made a float string here.
So, maybe instead of calling int, let's call float so that I can use my input.
And this will return a list of floats.
And you can make new instances of, you know, your custom classes in your list comprehension as well.